Guide to the Larry Spruch Papers MC.209
New York University Archives
- Series I: New York University, 1950-1999
  - Subseries A: Course Materials, 1950-1999
    - Quantum Mechanics problems, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Mathematical Physics problems, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Notes on perturbation theory, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Astrophysics I: Atoms in the magnetic field of a neutron star, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Notes for undergraduate Electricity and Magnetism course, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Reitz and Milford textbook: electricity and magnetism problems and notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Physics 294: Special Topics, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Undergraduate Mathematical Physics, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Notes for Intelligent Life in the Universe, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Notes for Physics and Society, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Problems on relativity, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Physics and Society, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Scattering Theory lecture notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Literature of Modern Ireland course materials: David H. Greene, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Problems from Jackson, undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Problems on various topics, undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Problems on various topics, undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Students' notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Astrophysics, undated (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Mathematical Physics notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Notes and problems from Ter Haar, Problems in Quantum Mechanics, undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Problems from Sakurai, undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Statistical Mechanics, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Physics and Society exam, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Notes on the age of the universe, for Intelligent Life in the Universe, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Notes for Intelligent Life in the Universe, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Boas' Mathematical Methods: problems, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Problems from David Park, Introduction to the Quantum Theory, chapters 3-5, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Quantum Mechanics problems from Park, chapter 6, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Quantum Mechanics problems from Park, chapters 7 and 8, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Quantum Mechanics problems from Park, chapters 9-11, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Coleman Quantum Mechanics Outline, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Physics 193: Atomic Physics, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Physics 193: Atomic Physics final exam, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Problems for Methods of Mathematical Physics, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Electromagnetism problems from Batygin and Toptygin text, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Notes on S. Chandrasekhar text on stellar structure, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Astrophysics problems, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Graduate Astrophysics lecture notes and problems, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Sample quantum exam problems, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Physics 292: Quantum Mechanics, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Physics 292: Quantum Mechanics, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Physics 292: Quantum Mechanics, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Cosmics, NYU Physics graduate student newsletter, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Course evaluations for Electricity and Magnetism, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Useful equations and numbers, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Gauge Theories lecture notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Many Body Theory lecture notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Notes on Feynman, for Physics 277 and 278: Quantum Theory of Fields, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Physics problem book cover forms, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Uncertainty Principle problem book, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Notes on Arnold Sommerfeld: Relativity, for Physics 271/272 course, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Quantum Mechanics course materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Undergraduate-level dynamics problems, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Quantum Mechanics problems, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Physics as a Liberal Art bibliography and article by I. L. Morgan on applications of nuclear and atomic technology, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Dynamics notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Atomic Theory notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Lecture notes on quantization, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Problems from Jackson, chapter 8, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Untitled problems, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Nuclear Physics lecture notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Quantum Mechanics lecture notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Nuclear Physics notes and problems, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Problems from Albert Messiah, Problems in Quantum Mechanics, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree, 1950-1961 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Quantum Mechanics preliminary examination for the Ph.D. degree, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. degree: Dynamics and Statistical Mechanics, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree, 1969, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree, 1975, 1980, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree, part III, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree: Quantum mechanics, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. degree, part II: Electricity and Magnetism, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Preliminary Examination for the Ph.D. Degree: Electricity and Magnetism, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Ph.D.s granted at NYU, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Physics and Society, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Subseries B: Faculty and Administrative Affairs, 1958-1999
    - Travel expenses, 1958-1971 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Annual report to Physics department, 1960, 1969-1971, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Faculty concerns, 1962-1969 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Travel expenses, 1966, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The Evaluation controversy, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Travel expenses, 1967-1970 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - GSAS and WSC matters, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Physics department statement on the Cambodian crisis, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Ivan L. Bennett affair, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Sigma Pi Sigma, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - NSF Committee on High Energy Physics, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Physics department, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - NSF committee, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Faculty concerns, 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Governance Committee - Physics department, 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Senior Fulbright-Hays Program, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - NSF Fellowship and Teaching Assistant holders, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Search committee for Physics department headship, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Physics department headship, 1972, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Physics department reading room acquisitions, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - NYU faculty union, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Faculty committee election results, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Faculty of Arts and Science personnel record supplements, 1974-1993 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - NYU Federation of United Professionals, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Physics department headship, 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - NYU operating budget for 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Report to the Dean for faculty records, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Faculty of Arts and Science senatorial election, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Sabbaticals, 1980-1992 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Faculty meeting, May 1982 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - NYU Urban Research Center Annual Report, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Graduate Curriculum Committee members, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Faculty of Arts and Science student disciplinary procedures, 1983-1988 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Physics department research report, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Executive Council, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - University Planning Commission, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Mellon Humanities Seminars for Visiting Scholars, 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Search Committee, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - James Arthur Lecture Series on Time and its Mysteries, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Faculty Council Benefits Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Mandatory Retirement, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Faculty profiles, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Flier for "A Living History Event" with Edward Gerjuoy and Sidney Borowitz, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Graph showing year of Ph.D. and salary, undated (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Summary of research in progress at NYU, undated (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Subseries C: Student Dissertations and Theses, 1951-1989
    - Stone Master's Thesis: Methods of Dimensional Analysis, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Sentner Master's Thesis: Dead Time Losses in Counting Systems, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Russek Dissertation: Interaction Moment Contributions to Magnetic Moments of Nuclei, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Kainer Master's Thesis: Some Considerations on Coulomb Scattering, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Brudner Master's Thesis: Radiation from an Undersea Horizontal Dipole, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Sternheim Master's Thesis: The Hydrogen Lien and Radio Astronomy, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Bartram Master's Thesis: Some Applications of Variational Methods, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Rossi Master's Thesis: Applications of Variational Methods to the Theory of Scattering, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Kelly Dissertation: Bounds of Scattering Phase Shifts, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Gold Dissertation: On Internal Bremsstrahlung, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - R. Bartram dissertation: one-dimensional and multi-channel scattering, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - R. Bartram dissertation: Appendix, with Spruch's notes, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Bartram Dissertation: Bounds on the Independent Elements of the Scattering Matrix for Some Multi-Channel Problems, 1960 (Box 9, File 13)
    - Epstein Dissertation: Bounds on Scattering Phase Shifts for the Dirac Equation, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Kalikstein Dissertation: Upper Bounds on Scattering Length and Low Energy Proton-Deuteron and Neutron-Deuteron Scattering, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - "Wally's Thesis" (untitled manuscript), 1963 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Berger Dissertation: Modified Effective Range Theory Expansions for Long Range Effective Potentials, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Aronson Dissertation: Resonances in the Elastic Scattering of Electrons by Hydrogen Atoms, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Henry Dissertation: Variational Lower Bounds on Electron Hydrogen S-Wave Phase Shifts, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Madhyastha thesis: Neutrino Pair Emission by Stellar (a) Plasmon-Plasmon, (b) Plasmon-Phonon, and (c) Phonon-Phonon Processes, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Mueller Dissertation: Atoms in Intense Magnetic Fields and An Attractive Alternative to the Thomas-Fermi Model of Atoms, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Tolchin Dissertation: Variational Methods for Many-Body Problems, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Luger Dissertation: Construction of Multi-Particle Green's Functions, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Winter thesis: The Effects of Long Range Potential on the Soft Photon Theorem and on Inelastic Threshold Scattering, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Lapicki Dissertation: Coulomb Ionization of Inner Shells by Heavy Charged Particles, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Wallace Dissertation: Kinematic Effects of Relativistic Objects, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - James F. Babb thesis proposal: Retardation Effects in a Helium Rydberg Atom and Other Atomic Systems, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Shiwei Li Ph.D. thesis proposal: Density Functional Theory of Atoms in Strong Magnetic Fields, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Hinckelmann Master's thesis: Low Engery Scattering by Long-Range r-4 Potentials, undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Kalikstein Thesis and Notes: Jacobian Method, undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Kiel Master's Thesis: A New Method for Determining the Velocity Distribution of Cosmic Ray Protons, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Untitled dissertation on density matrices, undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Rotenberg Dissertation: Interactions Contribution to Nuclear Isomerism, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1941-2005
  Series II is largely made up of Larry Spruch's professional correspondence, as well as some personal correspondence. The majority of the correspondence in the Larry Spruch Papers is located in this series, though the occasional letter may also be found in Series IV and Series V, as Spruch filed correspondence about certain articles or projects alongside the other related materials.
  - Personal correspondence, 1941-1991 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Personal correspondence: Sylvia Javornsky and Grace Marmor Spruch, 1942, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - General correspondence, 1946-2000 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Jackson, David S., 1951 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Letters, 1954-1958 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Letters received, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing letters, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Dalitz, Dick, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Letters received, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Outgoing letters, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Rosenberg, Leonard, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Wheeler, John A. (reprint request), 1960 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Lawrence Radiation Laboratory, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - University of California Lawrence Radiation Laboratory, 1960-1966 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Outgoing letters, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Letters received, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Letters to be answered, 1961-1963 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Letters received, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Outgoing letters, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Letters received, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Outgoing letters, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Phillips, Roger, United Kingdom Atomic Energy Research Establishment, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Hasted, J.B., Third International Conference on the Physics of Electronic and Atomic Collisions, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence re: visit to University of Wrocław, Poland, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Letters - sabbatical, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Outgoing and received letters, Fall 1964 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - "Odds and Ends"/Assorted correspondence, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Guillosset, Marie-Cécile, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Research Associate, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Reprint requests, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Requests for reprints, 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Ryb, George and Yukap Hahn: correspondence re: bound states, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Unanswered letters, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: Postdoctoral position, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Soviet Union visit, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Sabbatical in France, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Yeigele, Bill, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Gerjuoy, Edward, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - J. Robert Oppenheimer Memorial Prize committee, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Rau, A.R.P., 1972-1992 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Rau, A. R. P.: correspondence re: lower bounds on atomic energies, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - New York University Press, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Rice University Department of Physics, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Addison-Wesley Publishing Company, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Committee of Concerned Scientists, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Rau, A. R. P., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Scientists and Engineers for Social and Political Action, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Reprint requests, 1974, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence with R. H. Tucker (Physical Review A) and A. R. P. Rau re: article manuscript, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Rau, A. R. P.: Correspondence re: error in BLP paper, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Norcross, David, 1975, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Joint Institute for Laboratory Astrophysics, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Rau, A. R. P.: correspondence re: leading Thomas-Fermi Model correction, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Outgoing and received letters: sabbatical at Harvard, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Armour, E. A. G., 1977 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Review of Modern Physics, re: article written with Robin Shakeshaft, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence with The Physical Review re: Larry Spruch and Edward J. Kelsey manuscript, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Wadehra, Jogindra, 1977-1981 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Scientists for Orlov and Shcharansky, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Levy, Peter M. (Chair, NYU Department of Physics), 1979 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Postcard from Werner [?], 1979 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Shakeshaft, Robin, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence re: talk given in Kyoto, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Benjamin Bederson, Physical Review A, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Benjamin Bederson and Carol Kramer, Physical Review A, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Carol Kramer, Physical Review A, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Committee of Concerned Scientists, Inc., 1980 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Postcards, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - G. Barton and Robin Shakeshaft, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Tang, Yau C., 1982 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Dmitrieva, I., 1982 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Roni [?], re: Science Quizzes, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Claus [?], Westfälische Wilhelms-Universität Münster, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Trigg, George L. (editor of Physical Review Letters), 1983 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Reprint requests, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - NYU Urban Research Center, 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence re: Victor Weisskopf (NYU honorary degree and Nobel Prize nominations), 1984-1989 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - Ministerio de Educación Consejo Nacional de Investigaciones Científicas y Técnicas (Argentina), 1985 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Shakeshaft, Robin and Berthold-Georg Englert, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence with Reviews of Modern Physics, 1985-1991 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - Dean C. Duncan Rice, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 62)
  - Extremera, Alfonso (reprint request), 1987 (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - Lubkin, Gloria B., Physics Today, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - Berlowitz, Leslie Cohen (NYU Associate Vice President for Academic Affairs), 1987 (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence with Physical Review A and Physical Review Letters, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - Pratt, Richard H., National Science Foundation, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 68)
  - Berbevich, Thomas, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics Institute for Theoretical Atomic and Molecular Physics, 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - NYU Faculty Resource Network, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Letter to the Editor of Physics Today, 1990-1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Belay, Kidane and Susana Vallejo, 1990, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Tangherlini, Frank R. (preprint request), 1992 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Weidenmüller, Hans and Sieglinde Roederer, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Physics World, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - National Institute of Standards and Technology: Davisson-Germer Award selection committee, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Watwan, Abdullah (reprint request), 1992 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Levi, Barbara, Physics Today, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Brownstein, Kenneth R., 1993 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Augustiniak, Wlodzimierz (reprint request), 1993 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Postdoc applicants, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Postdoc applicants, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Frischat, Steffen D., 1995 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Weidenmüller, Hans, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence re: referee reports for "Near-Degeneracy Effect on Polarization of Energy Shifts in Some Highly-Charged Few-Electron Rydberg Ions", 1996 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - National Science Foundation proposal reviews, 1996-1997 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Brooklyn College, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Stranahan, George, 1999, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Babb, James F., 2000 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Taylor and Francis, Inc., 2000 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Brainerd, Beth, Institute for Advanced Study, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence with The Industrial Physicist re: quantum stickiness, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence with Tough Puzzles re: Alpha cipher, 2000-2002 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - University Archives' acquisition of Thomas E. Suttles' Ph.D. dissertation in physics, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Macaulife, Neville, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Outgoing and received letters, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - The New Yorker, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - University of Delaware, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Obermayer German-Jewish History Award, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Atlantic Monthly, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Kleppner, Dan, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Letter to the Editor of Physics Today, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Dobrydnev, Boris, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Fragment of a reprint request, undated (Box 12, Folder 48)